Guide to the Carnochan Family Papers, 1745-1929
Department of Special Collections
- Correspondence
  - Carnochan incoming
    - R-----, July 28, 1857-Aug. 12, 1871 (Box 5, Folder 32)
      J.W. Richards to J.M.C. July 28, 1857; Richmond Medical Profession banquet invitation, n.d. Includes calling cards.; Russian Imperiale Legation to J.M.C. Aug. 12, 1871; Consulate General of Russia to J.M.C. Aug. 12, 1871
    - S - T, Jan. 4, 1859-Mar. 10, 1871 (Box 5, Folder 33)
      6 letters D.E. Sickles to J.M.C. June 23, 1866, 2 n.d.; E.M. Stanton to E.M.C. June 23, 1869, includes card; B. Tucker to M.C. Jan. 4, 1859; W. Tweed to J.M.C. Mar. 10, 1871
    - Ann VanderHorst, May 8, 1857-Mar. 8, 1877 (Box 5, Folder 34)
      3 letters A. VanderHorst to E.M.C. May 8, 1857, Dec. 12, 1869, Mar. 8, 1877
    - W-----, Jan. 27, 1862-Jan. 26, 1886 (Box 5, Folder 35)
      8 letters S. Webster to J.M.C. Dec. 6, 1870; A. White to J.M.C. Apr. 4, 1868, Apr. 29, 1868; R. Williams to E.M.C. Jan. 27, 1862, Dec. 15, 1862, Dec. 20, 1862 (telegrams), Jan. 13, 1863; W. Winter to J.M.C. Jan. 26, 1886
    - Unknown, Jan. 20, 1853-Aug. 7, 1881 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      6 letters To to E.M.C. dated Jan. 20, 1853; To J.M.C. dated July 9, 1861; To dated Jan. 22, 1863 (anonymous thanks from Southerner during Civil War); To to J.M.C dated Aug. 17, 1870; To to J.M.C. Aug. 7, 1881; 1 fragment
    - Unknown, Dec. 10, 1856 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      To J.M.C. dated Dec. 10, 1856
    - [Minna] Schubert incoming, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 3)
      Madame Schubert was governess to the Carnochan children; 8 letters, 1 postcard from various people, many sending thanks for the care of their children. Several in Russian
    - Hackett and Knox, Oct. 15, 1842-Mar. 21, 1879 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      2 letters, relationship to the Carnochans unknown; E. G--to Mrs. J. Hackett Mar. 21, 1879; R. Knox to W. Ferguson Oct. 15, 1842
  - Lambard Outgoing
    - Allen Lambard, Feb. 14, 1825-Aug. 26, 1863 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      4 letters A.L. to Sibyll F. Lambard Feb. 14, 1825, Apr. 11, 1852; A.L. to Oroville Lambard July 11, 1863, Aug. 4, 1863, Aug. 26, 1863
    - Orville Dewey Lambard, Dec. 18, 1875-Mar. 15, 1883 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      2 letters O.L. to mother S. F. Lambard Dec. 18, 1875; O.L. to sister S. Baldwin and children Mar. 15, 1893
    - Sibyl Farnham Lambard, Oct. 6, 1835-Nov. 6, 1875 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      2 letters S.F.L to H.E.Farnham Oct. 6, 1835; S.F.L. to grandaughters [Sibyl, Katherine, Marie Baldwin] Nov. 6, 1875
    - Thomas Lambard, Aug. 25, 1879 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      1 letter T.L. to S.F. Lambard Aug. 25, 1879
  - Farnham Outgoing
    - Phebe Farnham Cobb, May 5, 1823-July 29, 1859 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      3 letters Phebe F. Cobb is twin sister of S. F. Lambard; S.F. Cobb to O. Dewey May 5, 1823; S.F. Cobb to L. Dewey -/14, 1824, July 29, 1859
  - Baldwin Outgoing
    - Henry Porter Baldwin, Apr. 2, 1877-Feb. 6, 1888 (Box 6, Folder 10)
      6 letters H.P.B. to K. Baldwin (Bliss) Apr. 2, 1877; H.P.B. to O. Lambard Sept. 12, 1878, Sept. 1, 1879, July 5, 1881; H.P.B. to M---June 4, 1886; Mr. and Mrs. Blanchard Feb. 6, 1888
    - Katherine Baldwin Bliss, [Apr. 15, 1894] (Box 6, Folder 11)
      1 letter, n.d. [Apr. 15, 1894] K.B.B. to S.L.B.
    - Sibyl Lambard Baldwin, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 12)
      3 letters, n.d. S.L.B. to sister C.L. Armitage
  - Baldwin Incoming
    - Baldwin incoming, Jan. 2, 1871-June 24 1907 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      8 letters, includes 1 picture Grand Duke Alexis to H.P.B. Jan. 2, 1871 with picture of Grand Duke; C. C. Trowbridge to H.P.B. May 28, 1880, Nov. 4, 1887; R.B. Hayes to H.P.B. Aug. 27, 1879, Sept. 6, 1879; K.B.B. to S.L.B. Sept. 25 [1903]; S. Hart to S.L.B June 24 1907; J. Whitmore to K.B.B. n.d.
    - Baldwin invitations, Feb. 3, 1881-Feb. 11, 1888 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      3 invitations President and Mrs. Hayes to Baldwins Feb. 3, 1881, Feb. 24, 1881; Invitation to Palais d'abome Feb. 11, 1888
  - Bliss Outgoing
    - George Bliss, Dec. 26, 1884 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      1 letter G.B. to Ingalls Dec. 26, 1884
  - Bliss Incoming
    - Opening ceremonies for Brooklyn Bridge, May 24, 1883 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      1 invitation and ticket May 24, 1883
    - President Garfield memorial service, Sept. 26, 1884 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      1 invitation Sept. 26, 1884
    - George Washington centennial celebration, Apr. 29, 1889 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      2 invitations and 2 tickets Apr. 30, 1889, May 30, 1889
    - President Harrison inagural invitation, Mar. 4, 1889 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      1 invitation and order of progression Apr. 3, 1889
    - Dinner for William Walter Phelps, Dec. 5, 1890 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      1 invitation, with menu and guest list Dec. 5, 1890
  - Farnham Album
    This sub-series is a facsimile of the "Farnham Album," a collection of Farnham family letters, genealogies, poems, etc. dating from 1745-1845. The originals are held by the Massachusetts Historical Society.
    - Introductory letter from John Farnham June 28, 1833,genealogies, and an account of the collection of album by Charlotte Farnham Leonard (1850.) (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Letters dating Apr. 29, 1745 -Oct. 30, 1773 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Letters dating Feb. 21, 1776 -Nov. 28, 1790 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Letters dating Dec. 3, 1790 -Oct. 22, 1800 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Letters dating Sept. 29, 1801 -June 20, 1807 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Letters dating July 20, 1809 -Nov. 4, 1813 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Letters dating July 1, 1815 -Jan. 20, 1818 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Letters dating June 4, 1819 -May 18, 1821 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Letters dating July 2, 1821 -June 15, 1822 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Letters dating Dec. 6, 1822 -June 1, 1823 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Letters dating Jan. 1, 1824 -Sept. 22, 1825 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Letters dating Mar. 1, 1825 -Oct. 31, 1825 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Letters dating Jan. 14, 1826 -Dec. 23, 1826 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Letters dating May 30, 1827 -Jan. 20, 1831 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Letters dating Jan. 8, 1832 -Nov. 12, 1845 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Undated and miscellaneous items in Farnham album. (Box 7, Folder 16)
      Contains letters, poems, certificates, obituaries and drawings
- Documents and Ephemera
  - Morris Family
    - Alexander family history "copied from the catalogue of the officers and alumni of The Washington and Lee University...Historical Sketches" (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Morris children school certificates and note, 1855 and n.d. (Box 8, Folder 2)
      6 school certificates; 1 small note with pressed flowers [G.W.M. to M.A.M. 1855?]
    - Poetry, 1838-1879 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      7 poems M.A.M. Oct. 14, 1838, Oct. 3, 1874, Feb. 28, 1879; E.M.C to M.A.M June 12, 1873; 4 n.d.
    - Programme of songs and clipping (Box 8, Folder 4)
      Programme of songs [presumably played at W.W.M.'s funeral]. Clipping taped to reverse side regarding W.W.M.'s post-mortem appointment to Major-General, and W.G.M.'s appointment as Major.
    - List of items lost in fire, Feb. 8, 1831 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      1 inventory of items lost in fire Feb. 7, 1831
    - Receipts, May 10, 1866 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      8 receipts A. [1779], May 5, 1801, [1802], Apr. 9, 1804; W.W. Morris Dec. 30, 1823; S. Forrester Oct. 31, 1848 payment to "Negro Interpreter" for service with Indians; H. Ritchie Aug. 16, 1854; M.A.M. May 10, 1866
    - Land bequest, Aug. 23, 1855 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      1 bequest of Perth Amboy Aug. 23, 1855
    - Florida Seminole battle report, Nov. 26, 1836 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      1 report detailing Indian battle in Florida Nov. 26, 1836
    - Florida Seminole battle report, Feb. 16, 1842 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      1 printed report Indian wars Feb. 16, 1842
    - Artillery glossary (Box 8, Folder 10)
      1 page describing (with illustrations) various bullets
    - William W. Morris military history, Feb. 19, 1869 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      1 transcription of W.W.M.'s military history. Transcribed by M.A.M. Feb. 19, 1869 from the Adjutant General's office [E.D. Townsend]
    - Newsclippings, Sept. 1, 1865 and n.d. (Box 8, Folder 12)
      3 clippings, 2.n.d.; I.O.O.F. speeches and ceremony report Sept. 21, 1865; W.G.M. career notices, n.d.
    - Calling cards (Box 8, Folder 13)
      Miscellaneous calling cards given to the Morris and Carnochan families
    - Jubilee coin (Box 8, Folder 31)
      1 commemerative coin date 1837 with annotation "received July 10 1898" by unknown
    - Locks of hair (Box 8, Folder 32)
      3 locks of hair from M.A.M. and W.W.M.
    - Army commissions (Box 10)
    - Maps (Box 11)
    - Morris deed and mortgage, May 2, 1840-Jan. 30, 1843 (Box 23, Folder 4)
      Lewis Morris mortgage 1840; Gouverneur Morris deed 1843
    - Mary Morris wills, June, Oct. 1878 (Box 23, Folder 5)
      3 copies M.A.M.'s will; 1 typed copy Oct. 1878; 2 written June 1878
    - Sally Ritchie will, July 25, 1844 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Ritchie lands tax sheet, Mar. 15, 1868 (Box 23, Folder 7)
      List of taxes due on Ritchie lands; B. Boyett to M. Simpson Mar. 15, 1868
    - Army and Navy Gazette, July 26, 1864(fragment) (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Pedigree of Morris, n.d. (Box 24)
  - Carnochan Family
    - Fragmenta antiquarium..., Aug. 28, 1827 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      Poem transcription by young J.M.C.?
    - University of Edinburgh course schedule, Sept. 30, 1842 (Box 8, Folder 15)
      1 listing of classes with times and instructors
    - Consular certificates, Oct. 25, 1845-Sept. 17, 1846 (Box 8, Folder 16)
      3 consular certificates Oct. 25, 1845, Sept. 17, 1846 (2)
    - Financial statements, Jan. 23, 1846-Mar. 12, 1847 (Box 8, Folder 17)
      4 financial statements Jan. 23, 1846-Mar. 12, 1847
    - Financial statements, Apr. 16, 1847-Apr. 7, 1881 (Box 8, Folder 18)
      7 financial statements, 1 check
    - War Department pass, May 12, 1866,for travel to Frederickburg (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - 1 card explaining J.M.C.'s billing practice, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - J.M. Carnochan obituary, National Cyclopedia entry and photocopy of Biographical Sketches of Distinguished Living New York Surgeons (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Transactions from October session of Medico-Legal Society [Oct. 12, 1887](3) (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Picture of New York Emigrant Hospital, Ward's Island [torn from book] (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Carnochan deed, Oct. 24, 1845 (Box 23, Folder 9)
      1 deed of Scottish house 1845
    - Rental agreement, Feb. 1, 1858 (Box 23, Folder 10)
      1 housing rental agreement 1858
    - Memorandum of agreement, Mar. 17, 1858-Feb. 15, 1877 (Box 23, Folder 11)
      Harper and Brothers memo regarding publication of J.M.C.'s "Contributions to Operative Surgery" 1877 (2)
    - Memorandum of sales, June 26, 1888,from Harpers Brothers (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Carnochan speeches, Sept. 9, 1887 (Box 23, Folder 13)
      2 speeches J.M.C. to Section on General Surgery "Congenital Dislocation of the Hip Joint"; J.M.C. to Section on General Surgery "Bony Union of Intra-Capsular Fracture of the Neck of the Femur", n.d.
    - Harper's Weekly and The Cyclopedia of American Biography, June 3, 1876 and n. d. (Box 23, Folder 14)
      Typed copies (2) of Harper's Weekly article on J.M.C. (1876); Typed copies (2) of Cyclopedia of American Biography entry, n.d.; Includes handwritten note (E.M.C.?) regarding J.M.C.'s ommission from Physicians and Surgeons Hall of Fame
  - Lambard Family
    - Allen Lambard Memorial booklets (3), n.d. [1877] (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Lambard family Bible pages (Box 9)
  - Baldwin Family
    - Baldwin certificates, 1866 Nov. 16-1871 Nov. 8 (Box 8, Folder 25)
      3 certificates: H.P.B. and S.A.L. marriage intention certificate 1866 Nov. 20; H.P.B. election certificate 1868 Dec. 8; H.P.B. Thanksgiving Day decree 1871 Nov. 8
    - Newsclippings, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 26)
      2 clippings: Description of interior of Baldwin home, n.d.; Purchase of Baldwin home for bank, n.d.
    - Menus, 1871 Dec. 29 -1887 Feb. 19 (Box 8, Folder 27)
      H.P.B. menus and guest lists. 2 n.d.
  - Bliss Family
    - George Bliss, Last will and testament (2), n.d. [1901] (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - George Bliss biography - National Cyclopedia entry (Box 8, Folder 29)
- Books
  - Baldwin Family
    - Legislative Proceedings: Memorial of Rutherford B. Hayes and Henry P. Baldwin, 1893(2 books) (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - In Memory of the Honorable Henry Porter Baldwin of Detroit, 1893(1 book) (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Baldwin Genealogy and Supplement (2 volumes) (Box 17)
    - Baldwin - Bliss (Box 18)
      4 books: Bliss family genealogy
      Baldwin's copy of Constitutional Manual. Includes Constitution, Amendments, Declaration of Independence, Rules of the Senate, etc.
      Baldwin's gubernatorial Messages. Includes his inaugural and retiring messages, messages to legislature, pardons granted, proclamations, etc.
      Historical Address (annotated "mention of Reverand Moses Baldwin")
    - Michigan Wayne County Chronography and Pioneer Biography (1 book) (Box 19)
  - Bliss Family
    - Katherine Baldwin Bliss genealogies (Box 15)
      2 volumes: The genealogical chart of the paternal American ancestry of Mrs. Walter Phelps Bliss (Katherine Baldwin)-The Baldwin and allied families.
      The genealogical chart of the maternal American ancestry of Mrs. Walther Phelps Bliss (Katherine Baldwin) The Lambard-Farnham and allied families.
  - Carnochan Family
    - Address on the Study of Science, 1857 Oct. 20(3, 2 bound) (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Cerebral Localization in Relation to Insanity, 1884(1 book) (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Contributions to Operative Surgery and Surgical Pathology, 8 volumes, 1877-1887 (Box 12)
    - Carnochan Genealogy (Box 14)
  - Morris Family
    - Army Register and List of Appointments, 1858 Jan. 1-1865 Aug. 22 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      2 books: Official Army Register for 1858
      Listing of appointments 1865
      Annotation by E.M.C. "This book (register) was the last thing my dear Father gave me and wrote my name on it about a month before he died."
    - Descendants of Lewis Morris of Morrisania, 1 genealogy (Box 13)
  - Parsons Family
    - Parsons Family Genealogy, 2 volumes (Box 16, Folder x)
- Photographs
  - Morris Family
    - Cartes de visites (in album) of Civil War Army officials (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Carnochan Family
    - Estelle Morris Carnochan (Box 21, Folder 2)
      1 photo (in album) of E.M.C. in wedding dress
    - John Murray Carnochan (Box 21, Folder 3)
      1 photo (in album) of J.M.C.
    - John M. Carnochan and infant (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
      2 photos (in album) of J.M.C. and unidentified infant (duplicate)
    - Carnochan tombs (Box 22, Folder 3)
      2 photos Carnochan tombs [Charleston, South Carolina]